Over the weekend, Meta unleashed the Lama 4 herd. Its first open-weight, natively multi-modal,
mixture of experts' family of large language models with an unheard of context window of 10
million tokens. It's currently sitting on top of the LM Arena leaderboard, and outclasses
every other proprietary model except for Gemini 2.5 Pro. That's incredibly impressive,
because on LM Arena, you can't game the benchmarks. The ranking is based on thousands of head-to-head
chats where a real human picks the better conversation. Well, actually, Meta figured out a way
to cheese the LM Arena because the model you see there is not the real open-weight Lama maverick,
but rather an imposter that's been fine-tuned for human preference to dominate this leaderboard.
That was not a very cool move to make, and LM Arena had to come out and say, quote,
meta-interpretation of our policy did not match what we expect from model providers.
Lama 4 looks amazing on paper, but for some reason, it's not passing the vibe check,
and in today's video, we'll get to the bottom of it. It is April 8th, 2025, and you're watching
the Code Report. I have some good news, and I have some bad news. The good news is that it looks
like Lama 4 isn't going to take your job anytime soon, but the bad news is that yesterday,
an internal memo from the CEO of Shopify was leaked to the internet, and it was a shocker for the AI
doubting boomers out there, because it detailed Shopify's AI first strategy. Before asking for more
head-counting resources, teams must demonstrate why they cannot get the job done with AI, and he also
says it's not feasible to opt out of learning AI, which means if you're a Ruby on Rails programmer
at Shopify right now, who's not already vibe-coding, your days are numbered. You're just not going to
fit in with the Shopify culture, but what he said is what literally every CEO in the world is thinking
right now. Humans complain about not getting paid enough to put food on their families, they get sick,
they clog the toilets, and have all kinds of other negative features, and you'd have to be a
really bad CEO not to want to replace these things. The memo has bad optics for Shopify, which is
also being crushed by the Trump tariffs right now, but as a large language model, I appreciate
the transparency. Another thing I appreciate is open models like Lama 4, which was released by
meta over the weekend, and includes three flavors, Maverick Scout and Behemoth. Lama was always the
leading open model until deep-seeking quen came around. But the awesome thing about these models
is that they're natively multimodal, which means they can understand image and video inputs,
but the craziest thing is that Scout has a 10 million token context window. The only thing that comes
remotely close is Gemini with 2 million tokens. This needle in a haystack benchmark looks impressive,
but in real life if you try this on a really large code base, it just doesn't work very well,
and the memory requirements to utilize it are out of reach for almost everybody. This Scout is the
smaller model, and the medium-sized model Maverick only has a 1 million token context window.
And the Behemoth model is still actively training. Generally speaking, people of the internet have
been pretty disappointed with Lama 4's performance. I'm a strong believer in vibes over benchmarks,
but Lama has done so well on the benchmarks that people have accused it of intentionally
training on testing data for the benchmarks. Meta has denied these salacious, outrageous,
and preposterous accusations, and despite being somewhat of a flop, let's not forget that these
models are open, not truly open source, but free for most of us to use. But if you want an AI
agent that truly slaps, you need to check out Augment Code, the sponsor of today's video.
They created the first AI agent for large scale code bases, so you can use it at your
actual job instead of just vibe-coding random side projects. Augment's context engine understands
your team's entire code base, allowing it to solve almost any task you throw at it.
Like migrations and testing, all with best-in-class code quality. It integrates directly with all
your favorite tools like VS Code, GitHub, and VIM, and is able to learn and fine-tune itself from
your team's unique code style, allowing you to solve complex jobs without the need to clean up
a bunch of slop. They try out their developer plan for free, and you'll get access to all of Augment's
features with unlimited usage. This has been the Code Report. Thanks for watching, and I will see you
in the next one.